[
  {
    "question_number": 1,
    "question": "البحرين : تونس",
    "choices": ["الكويت : الجزائر", "القاهرة : مسقط", "الدوحة : الرياض", "السودان : تركيا", "اليونان : إيطاليا"],
    "answer": "الكويت : الجزائر",
    "category": "علاقات الدول"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 2,
    "question": "الإسكندرية : الرياض",
    "choices": ["نيويورك : الدوحة", "عدن : الخرطوم", "جدة : جاكرتا", "المنامة : الكويت"],
    "answer": "عدن : الخرطوم",
    "category": "علاقات الدول"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 3,
    "question": "أم القرى : مكة",
    "choices": ["المدينة : طيبة", "خيبر : عرفات", "يثرب : الطائف", "منى : مزدلفة"],
    "answer": "المدينة : طيبة",
    "category": "علاقات الدول"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 4,
    "question": "مصر : السودان",
    "choices": ["السعودية : اليمن", "العراق : ليبيا", "سوريا : الشام", "المغرب : جزر القمر"],
    "answer": "السعودية : اليمن",
    "category": "علاقات الدول"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 5,
    "question": "لبنان : صيدا",
    "choices": ["السعودية : جدة", "السودان : الخرطوم", "الأردن : جرش", "العراق : الموصل"],
    "answer": "السعودية : جدة",
    "category": "علاقات الدول"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 6,
    "question": "مسكن : واسع",
    "choices": ["طعام : شهي", "كتاب : مفيد", "مرسم : جميل", "صدر : ضيق"],
    "answer": "مرسم : جميل",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 7,
    "question": "قاضي : حكمة",
    "choices": ["محارب : جبن", "مقاتل : شجاعة", "ذكاء : تاجر", "طفل : مراهقة"],
    "answer": "مقاتل : شجاعة",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 8,
    "question": "الإنسان : العقل",
    "choices": ["الغزال : السرعة", "الوقت : الساعة", "الماء : الشرب", "اللوحة : الغرفة"],
    "answer": "الغزال : السرعة",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 9,
    "question": "امرأه : نجلاء",
    "choices": ["طفل : سمين", "تاجر : بخيل", "عطر : فواح", "جبل : وعر"],
    "answer": "عطر : فواح",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 10,
    "question": "حديد : صلب",
    "choices": ["كرم : سخاء", "تور : شمس", "سيل : جارف", "بناء : تشييد"],
    "answer": "سيل : جارف",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 11,
    "question": "قائد : محنك",
    "choices": ["أب : متسلط", "عالم : تواضع", "شجاع : فارس", "فيلسوف : مكثار"],
    "answer": "عالم : تواضع",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 12,
    "question": "جبال : رواسي",
    "choices": ["نجوم : مضيئة", "محطة : فندق", "روضة : أزهار", "أودية : أشجار"],
    "answer": "نجوم : مضيئة",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 13,
    "question": "ليل : أليل",
    "choices": ["شمس : مشمسة", "برق : صاعق", "هول : هائل", "نجم : لامع"],
    "answer": "شمس : مشمسة",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 14,
    "question": "منافق : مخادع",
    "choices": ["أسد : زئير", "أفعى : سم", "بعير : صبر", "غزال : قفز"],
    "answer": "بعير : صبر",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 15,
    "question": "ليل : حالك",
    "choices": ["حصان : أبيض", "شعر : أشقر", "شفة : لمياء", "عيون : حولاء"],
    "answer": "شفة : لمياء",
    "category": "علاقة الصفة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 16,
    "question": "مكواة : ثياب",
    "choices": ["لحم : سكين", "محراث : حقل", "مسمار : خشب", "ملعقة : مطبخ"],
    "answer": "محراث : حقل",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 17,
    "question": "نجار : منشار",
    "choices": ["سيلرة : قائد", "حجام : محجم", "سماعة : طبيب", "ورشة : حداد"],
    "answer": "حجام : محجم",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 18,
    "question": "مطرقة : قاضي",
    "choices": ["صدقة : فقير", "تاج : ملك", "عصا : راعي", "رتبة : عسكري"],
    "answer": "عصا : راعي",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 19,
    "question": "نجار : خشب",
    "choices": ["غواص : لؤلؤ", "حداد : مصنع", "معلم : حاسب", "موظف : مكتب"],
    "answer": "معلم : حاسب",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 20,
    "question": "منجل : حصد",
    "choices": ["دبابة : رشاش", "معول : هدم", "مجداف : بحار", "نصح : تربية"],
    "answer": "معول : هدم",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 21,
    "question": "خشب : نجار",
    "choices": ["دقيق : خباز", "سكين : جزار", "حداد : مطرقة", "صياد : شبكة"],
    "answer": "دقيق : خباز",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 22,
    "question": "نجار : خشب",
    "choices": ["صائد : شبكة", "حداد : مطرقة", "خباز : خبز", "خياط : قماش"],
    "answer": "خياط : قماش",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 23,
    "question": "كاميرا : التقاط",
    "choices": ["مسمار : جرح اليد", "زجاج : وضوح الرؤية", "ستارة : دفء", "قطار : نقل"],
    "answer": "قطار : نقل",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 24,
    "question": "رئة : تنفس",
    "choices": ["عقل : تفكير", "لسان : تذوق", "قدم : مشي", "أنف : شم"],
    "answer": "عقل : تفكير",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 25,
    "question": "المكيف : التبريد",
    "choices": ["المشاعر : الغضب", "مقص : حياكة", "العقل : ضبط", "مصابيح : دجى"],
    "answer": "العقل : ضبط",
    "category": "علاقة الآلية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 26,
    "question": "ذهب : ذهاب",
    "choices": ["جلس : جلوس", "غفر : غفار", "عمل : عمال", "رجع : راجع"],
    "answer": "جلس : جلوس",
    "category": "علاقة المصدر"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 27,
    "question": "سما : سمو",
    "choices": ["علا : علو", "يغدو : غدو", "عصا : عصو", "اشترى : مشتري"],
    "answer": "علا : علو",
    "category": "علاقة المصدر"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 28,
    "question": "غدا : غدو",
    "choices": ["غفر : غفار", "رجع : رجوع", "جلس : جالس", "سمع : سماع"],
    "answer": "رجع : رجوع",
    "category": "علاقة المصدر"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 29,
    "question": "نام : نوم",
    "choices": ["جميل : جمال", "نزل : نزول", "عصا : عصو", "يلعب : لاعب"],
    "answer": "نزل : نزول",
    "category": "علاقة المصدر"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 30,
    "question": "باع : بيع",
    "choices": ["مشى : مشي", "كبير : كبر", "يغدو : غدو", "يقرأ : قرأ"],
    "answer": "مشى : مشي",
    "category": "علاقة المصدر"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 31,
    "question": "عداوة : خداع",
    "choices": ["قريب : عزيز", "رحم : وصل", "بقاء : حياء", "نفور : غضب"],
    "answer": "رحم : وصل",
    "category": "علاقة الإقتران"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 32,
    "question": "قلق : توتر",
    "choices": ["مطر : غرق", "كتابة : تدوين", "تثبيت : وقوف", "وضوء : نظافة"],
    "answer": "وضوء : نظافة",
    "category": "علاقة الإقتران"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 33,
    "question": "صيف : حر",
    "choices": ["سماء : صفاء", "مطر : شمس", "برد : شتاء", "ليل : ظلام"],
    "answer": "ليل : ظلام",
    "category": "علاقة الإقتران"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 34,
    "question": "طهر : عفاف",
    "choices": ["أنانية : سوء", "قراءة : تأني", "رفيع : مستوى", "عداوة : خداع"],
    "answer": "عداوة : خداع",
    "category": "علاقة الإقتران"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 35,
    "question": "وضوء : نظافة",
    "choices": ["بقاء : حياء", "سماء : صفاء", "شتاء : برد", "قوة : بطش"],
    "answer": "شتاء : برد",
    "category": "علاقة الإقتران"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 36,
    "question": "الكعبة : المطاف",
    "choices": ["الورد : الحديقة", "المقام : الحجر الأسود", "الملتزم : الركن اليماني", "البيت : السور"],
    "answer": "البيت : السور",
    "category": "علاقة الإحاطة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 37,
    "question": "نطاق : خصر",
    "choices": ["سوار : معصم", "بيت : فناء", "الوطن : حدود", "ورد : حديقة"],
    "answer": "سوار : معصم",
    "category": "علاقة الإحاطة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 38,
    "question": "قشرة : برتقال",
    "choices": ["مزرعة : حبوب", "بحيرة : أسماك", "هالة : قمر", "محل : عسل"],
    "answer": "هالة : قمر",
    "category": "علاقة الإحاطة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 39,
    "question": "بيت : سور",
    "choices": ["مضمار : حصان", "شجرة : ثمرة", "عنق : عقد", "خيمة : عمود"],
    "answer": "عنق : عقد",
    "category": "علاقة الإحاطة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 40,
    "question": "الكعبة : المطاف",
    "choices": ["السور : البيت", "البطن : الحزام", "الحديقة : الورد", "مقام : حجر أسود"],
    "answer": "البطن : الحزام",
    "category": "علاقة الإحاطة"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 41,
    "question": "ريش : طائر",
    "choices": ["قماش : إنسان", "صوف : خروف", "زعانف : سمكة", "ستارة : نافذة"],
    "answer": "صوف : خروف",
    "category": "علاقة التغطية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 42,
    "question": "حذاء : قدم",
    "choices": ["سماعة : أذن", "قبعة : رأس", "نظارة : عين", "غطاء : إناء"],
    "answer": "قبعة : رأس",
    "category": "علاقة التغطية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 43,
    "question": "لحاء : شجرة",
    "choices": ["ياقة : عنق", "حجاب : وجه", "غطاء : علبة", "جلد : ثعبان"],
    "answer": "جلد : ثعبان",
    "category": "علاقة التغطية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 44,
    "question": "نهر : شاطئ",
    "choices": ["رصيف : شارع", "نص : هامش", "قماش : خياط", "إناء : غطاء"],
    "answer": "نص : هامش",
    "category": "علاقة التغطية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 45,
    "question": "حراشف : سمكة",
    "choices": ["ريش : طائر", "أنف : إنسان", "سمكة : زعانف", "أسد : زئير"],
    "answer": "ريش : طائر",
    "category": "علاقة التغطية"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 46,
    "question": "ولد : دلو",
    "choices": ["بحر : رحب", "غنى : طغيان", "كسوف : خسوف", "ليمون : حمضيات"],
    "answer": "بحر : رحب",
    "category": "علاقة عكس الحروف"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 47,
    "question": "راح : حار",
    "choices": ["لمح : حمل", "سكن : كنس", "بحر : ريح", "إبتعاد : إقتراب"],
    "answer": "لمح : حمل",
    "category": "علاقة عكس الحروف"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 48,
    "question": "باع : عاب",
    "choices": ["لحم : ملح", "مسح : حسم", "دار : در", "حضر : حاضر"],
    "answer": "مسح : حسم",
    "category": "علاقة عكس الحروف"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 49,
    "question": "ملح : حلم",
    "choices": ["روح : حور", "ليل : نوم", "اكل : شبع", "فقير : مسكين"],
    "answer": "روح : حور",
    "category": "علاقة عكس الحروف"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 50,
    "question": "ربح : حبر",
    "choices": ["لين : نيل", "قرأ : كتاب", "نار : دفء", "غرفه : باب"],
    "answer": "لين : نيل",
    "category": "علاقة عكس الحروف"
  }
]